[theme music]
♪ Everywhere you look ♪
♪ There's a heart ♪
♪ A hand to hold on to ♪
♪ Everywhere you look ♪
♪ There's a face ♪
♪ Of somebody
who needs you ♪
♪ Everywhere you look ♪
♪ When you're lost
out there ♪
♪ And you're all alone ♪
♪ A light is waiting ♪
♪ To carry you home ♪
♪ Everywhere you look ♪
♪ Everywhere you look ♪♪
♪ Ah ah ah ah ♪
[instrumental music]
Come on, everybody.
If we wanna get these
grape leaves ready
before great-grandpa
Katsopolis gets here
you guys are gonna
have to stuff faster.
I'm stuffing
as fast as I can.
Does grandpa have
a job back in Greece?
Oh, sweetheart,
don't you remember?
He used to be a fisherman.
Hey, Danny, you remember
when we were kids
we'd go fishing
with your dad?
Oh, yeah,
that was the life, wasn't it?
Out on the rolling seas.
I can still hear
my dad's voice
"Son, you ever been
this nauseous?"
Remember that promise
we made to each other?
I sure do.
We were gonna save
our money and buy a boat
and sail around the world.
Whatever happened
to that dream, Joey?
Same thing that happened
to all our dreams
Mr. Vice president.
See you, dad.
We're gonna go to the mall.
You just got back
from the mall.
I know, but I can't
stop thinking
about these designer's
sunglasses I saw.
They're round
with black metal frames.
And these really cool
dark purple lenses?
Yeah. Did you see them on that
styrofoam head at the store?
No, I see them on
the wooden head at the door.
- Kimmy.
- Cool shades, huh?
Kimmy, you always
do this to me.
Every time I see
something I like
you just have to have it.
Hey, I left Steve alone.
And don't think
I'm not grateful.
Kimmy, I don't want
to be seen together
wearing the exact
same glasses.
Maybe we shouldn't be
seen together at all.
- Fine with me.
Fine with me.
(Jesse)
'Hey, everybody,
we're home.'
He's here.
Hello, everybody.
(all)
Hey.
Oh. Mmm.
We missed you, grandpa.
You remember
the last time I was here?
I told you to
call me Papouli.
"Grandpa" means someone
who is old and gray.
What does Papouli mean?
In Greece, someone
who is old and gray
but it sounds
so much better.
Okay, okay, I'm next.
Papouli.
So, you remember me?
Of course, I do, Joey.
- I'm Danny.
- I'm, I'm Joey.
Of course, you are.
Ha ha ha ha.
And little Stephanie.
Oh..
- No, I'm D.J.
- Of course, you are.
And little Michelle.
Oh.
Mmm.
- I'm Stephanie.
- I'm little Michelle.
Of course, you are.
And you?
I have no idea who you are.
You have no idea
who any of us are.
Alright, fine.
Papoul, this is Steve.
- D.J.'s boyfriend.
- Ah-huh.
You'll be seeing him a lot,
probably in the kitchen.
- Hey, Deej, catch you later.
- Okay.
- Papouli, see you around.
- In the kitchen, right?
[laughing]
Papouli.
Hey, Papouli,
you remember Rebecca?
- Who could forget Rebecca?
- I bet you could.
And Papoul,
this is Nicky and Alex
'your great-grandchildren.'
Boys, say hi to Papouli.
- Hi, Papoodi.
Oh, give Papouli a kiss.
That's nice.
Moussaka.
Oh, Papouli's
famous moussaka.
Mmm.
Smell that, girls.
Smell that.
- Isn't that delicious?
- Mmm.
Papouli you have to give us
this recipe before you leave.
No problem.
This one I got off the back
of a box of moussaka helper.
[laughing]
Kimmy is the most
irritating person
in the entire world.
Welcome to our side.
You know, she wore those
sunglasses all day in school
even in gym.
What's wrong with that?
We were swimming.
I mean, she knew
I wanted those glasses.
And she knew I wouldn't wear
'em if she had 'em
but she bought 'em anyway.
You know, this sounds
like a fight
that two men
in my village had.
Nikos bought his wife
a beautiful pair
of pink ox-hair slippers.
Andreas found out about it
and then he bought
the very same slippers.
Well, maybe his wife
had cold feet.
Deej, Deej,
you're missing the point.
Now all of Papoulis' stories
have a lesson, okay?
And he's passing down the wisdom
of our Greek ancestors.
So you gotta listen okay?
This story is not just
about ox-hair slippers.
It's about..
...uh, well,
this, this particular story..
What's the story
about, Papouli?
It's about time
you shut up
and let me
finish the story.
Right.
The point is
that Andreas
wasn't even married.
He bought the slippers
because Nikos
had the slippers.
Well, he walked all around town
in those slippers.
'Course, he had
the legs to carry it off.
[both laughing]
- Anyway.
Uh, Nikos was
so mad at Andreas
he never spoke
to him again.
See. See, Deej?
Words to live by
from Papouli, okay?
Now you know
what he's talking about?
Mm-hmm. Andreas was a jerk
just like Kimmy.
Well, yes.
Yes, that's right.
Is that,
is that right, Papoul?
- Not right.
- That's not right, Deej.
Wow.
We got flour everywhere.
Don't worry.
When we got flour
on our hands
where do we wipe them off?
- On a towel?
- No, my little Michelle.
On our nose.
[laughing]
How about on our..
...cheeks?
That's the idea.
Only we missed a spot.
Opa.
Okay.
Oh, my goodness.
Opa.
Ho ho ho ho.
Hey, hey, hey,
hey, kids.
(all)
What?
You're making a mess here.
What mess?
This is a celebration.
- Opa.
Come on, Jesse,
get in the party.
- Okay
- Opa.
Okay, alright. I'll try.
Here we go, everybody. Ready?
Happy new year.
Opa.
- 'Opa.
- Opa. Opa.'
Okay, you want opa?
I'll give you opa.
Whoo hoo hoo.
Opa.
- Opa. Whoo.
- Ha-ha.
'Oh, boy.'
[Greek music]
Alright.
Uncle Jesse, Papoulis' teaching
me how to do a Greek dance.
Come on, Jesse.
We show her a couple steps, huh?
No, no, thanks, paupoli.
I really don't dance.
You're Greek.
You dance.
Papouli, am I Greek?
Of course, you are,
my little Michelle.
I don't feel Greek.
Well, to feel Greek
you must be proud.
Proud of your ancestors
the great authors
and thinkers.
Of course, you should enjoy
life a little bit, too.
That's why we dance
because we cannot
contain our happiness.
Right, Jesse?
Listen, my heart is Greek.
It just my feet
don't know it.
Listen, you guys have fun.
Dance.
I'm gonna go clean up the little
celebration in the kitchen.
- You're doing great, Michelle.
- Thank you.
Papouli, it's share time
at school next Monday.
Could you come and teach
my class a Greek dance?
Of course, I can,
my sweet little Michelle.
I love you, Papouli.
And I love you, too.
[instrumental music]
[slow instrumental music]
It's like a..
...a bad dream or something.
I know.
But you know
at least Papouli died
peacefully in his sleep
you know?
We know how much he
meant to you, Jess.
He meant a lot to us, too.
We're all gonna miss him.
It's just..
So helpless, it's like,
if I could have been there
I could have done something.
You know,
I could've helped him. I--
Jesse, honey.
Honey, honey.
There was nothing
that you could do.
that any of us could do.
You know.
You're right.
It's just that he was
such a beautiful man.
Just so full of
love and life.
Now he's gone.
Uncle Jesse..
...you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm fine. No, I-I
don't have time for this.
I got so many things to do,
make the arrangements--
We want to help.
Yeah, Jess, we-we can
take care of all that.
No. You know what,
it's-it's my responsibility.
I'm just..
I'm sorry, guys.
I'll-I'll-I'll take care of it.
Why won't Uncle Jesse
let us help him?
Oh, honey, it's just his way
of dealing with the pain,
you know, by keeping busy.
Hi, everybody.
Hi, Michelle.
Hi, daddy.
How was your
honeybee meeting?
It was great.
I made this for Papouli.
Where is he?
Michelle, Papouli's not here.
It's okay.
Something's wrong.
Uh, sweetheart,
this is, uh
this is not easy
to say to you.
Uh..
This morning after
you went to school
we went
to wake up Papouli.
Michelle, he died
in his sleep last night.
What?
He was, he was just..
He was very old
and his heart gave out.
No, he's not dead.
- Michelle.
- Why did Papouli have to die?
It's not fair.
I know.
It's a part of life, sweetie.
And Papouli led
a long and full life.
It makes me so mad.
It's okay to feel mad.
You lost somebody
that you love
but we're a family, right?
So, we're gonna help pull
each other through this.
Okay?
Okay.
Is there anything
you want to ask me?
No.
Okay, well, if you do
I'm here for you.
So if you have any questions
about what you're feeling
or about what happened,
you just come talk to me, okay?
Okay.
I love you.
- Hey, Michelle.
- 'Hi.'
- How you doin'?
- I feel like crying.
Me, too.
But we can't do that
in front of Uncle Jesse.
Why not?
'Cause if he saw us crying..
...he might start
to cry again, too.
Uncle Jesse
was crying?
He started to.
He didn't want me to see,
but I did.
Michelle, we gotta be
brave for Uncle Jesse.
And not let him know
that we're sad, too.
I don't know
if I can do that.
You have to.
But how can I stop
myself from crying?
Just think of
something funny
like, uh, when Joey stuffs a
whole doughnut in his mouth.
Yeah, that always
makes me laugh.
Alright, Aunt Elaine.
I'll be there in a few days.
Girls, you okay?
Yeah.
You alright, Michelle?
What are you doin'?
Thinking about Joey stuffing
a whole doughnut in his mouth.
Oh.
Alright.
Now, you girls
hang in there.
Just talked to
the relatives.
Looks like I'm going back
to Greece for a few days.
Good job, kid.
[instrumental music]
(Danny)
Ahoy, matey.
Whoa.
Danny, where'd you
get the boat?
What boat?
Oh, I, I bought it.
Danny, you went and bought
a boat, just like that?
It took you six months
to decide between
liquid or powder bleach.
Yeah, but, this is,
this is different.
This is something
we always dreamed about.
Isn't that right,
little buddy?
Aye-aye, captain.
I hear exactly
what you're saying.
You know, after everything
that's happened this week
it makes you realize
that your life's really short.
You should go for your dreams
or you got no reason
to wake up in the morning
and scratch yourself.
(Danny)
'I hear you.'
Hey, everybody,
check this out.
I think I got the perfect
name for our vessel.
Hey, Papouli.
I like it.
So do I
And so would Papouli.
Thanks, Danny.
You know, I gotta..
I'm gonna get back
on the phones
and...make a bunch of calls.
Jess.
You know,
you need to slow down
and take some time
for yourself.
Beck, I'll be fine.
I just wanna
call the airlines
and confirm that I,
I don't want
to end up
in Athens, Georgia.
Hey, Beavis and Boat-head.
Look, Joey,
we caught our first fish
the bigmouth Gibbler.
Too bad we can't
throw it back.
Guys, can we
have a minute?
Oh, sure.
Hi, Kimmy.
Hey, Deej.
Steve told me about
your great-grandpa.
I'm really sorry.
Thanks.
Listen, about
the sunglasses--
You know what,
forget about the sunglasses.
You know, I missed the whole
point to Papouli's story.
Yeah, Andreas was wrong,
but Nikos was wrong, too.
Andreas and Nikos?
Have you been hanging out with
those Irish exchange students?
No, Kimmy.
You know, we shouldn't break up
a lifelong friendship
over something as stupid
as a pair of sunglasses.
Yeah, you're right.
A sweater, maybe, but..
Friends again?
You got it.
How's Michelle?
She's fine.
What do you mean
she's not at school?
I saw her leave for school
this morning.
'Oh.'
Boy, I sure had a big lunch
but I got this one
pudding cup left.
What to do? What..
You know, I'll just..
I'll put it up here on the boat
next to the other one
and come back
and get it later.
Well, I'm off.
Gotcha.
That was cold.
Michelle, what are you doing
home from school?
I..
...couldn't find
my backpack.
What's that?
Oh, it's in the boat.
- It's in the boat.
- The one place I didn't look.
Hey, hey, shorty.
Hold on a second.
Come here.
Come on, shorty, level with me.
What's really going on?
I can't tell you.
You can't tell me?
We tell each other
everything.
- Everything?
- Yeah.
Well..
I never told you this,
but, uh..
I once bought
a Kathie Lee Gifford CD.
Oh, boy,
does that feel good
to get that
out in the open.
Alright, go ahead.
It's your turn.
Papouli was supposed to
come to school today
to teach my class
a Greek dance.
I'm sorry, kiddo.
I was afraid
if I went to school
and Papouli wasn't there
It felt sad.
Well, Michelle,
it's okay to feel sad.
But if I felt sad,
I might cry.
Then I can't be brave..
...for you.
Michelle..
...where'd you get the idea
that you had to
be brave for me?
From Stephanie.
She said that you were so sad
we shouldn't make you worse.
Oh, sweetheart..
Stephanie..
She probably thought
she was telling you
the right thing to do,
but she was wrong.
'I'm going to talk
to her about that.'
Michelle, we should..
we should always share
our feelings with each other.
That's what makes us
a family.
I really loved Papouli.
I was his little Michelle.
I was his little Jesse.
He used to always
take care of me.
Now he comes to visit me
and I can't even
take care of him.
It's not your fault.
His heart was old.
I know, Michelle,
but it still hurts.
It's okay to be sad.
I know I heard that
somewhere before.
Uncle Jesse?
Hmm?
Is it okay to cry?
You bet.
[crying]
Thank you, Denise.
That was very informative.
Are you gonna be okay?
Yeah.
Alright.
- Hi, Michelle.
- Hi.
Do you have something
for share time today?
Well...my great-grandpa Papouli
was supposed to come
to school today
to teach us
a Greek dance
but...he died.
Oh. Well, we're all
very sorry, Michelle.
He taught me some of it
but I'm not sure
if I can remember.
Well, I'm sure we'd all really
like it if you tried.
- Yeah.
Okay, I brought the tape.
"Hooked on Bazookee."
[Greek music]
I can't remember the rest.
(Jesse)
'I can.'
Ready?
Ready for the big jump,
Michelle?
Opa.
Here we go.
[all clapping]
♪ Ah ah ah ah ♪
[theme music]
♪ Shooby-do-ba-botta ♪♪